{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The sterilization method depends", "opta": "nature of additive", "optb": "volume and feed rate", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The specific death rate of an organism can be expressed as", "opta": "ln 2/D", "optb": "D/ln2", "optc": "D.ln2", "optd": "2.0.3/ln2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The interception efficiency can be expressed as (where dp is the particle diameter and Dc cylindrical collection diameter)", "opta": "dp/Dc", "optb": "dp x Dc", "optc": "dp/Dc x 100", "optd": "dpDc/100", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The relationship between the del factor, temperature and time is given as", "opta": "\u0394 = A.t. e-E/RT", "optb": "\u0394 = 1/(A.t. e-E/RT)", "optc": "\u0394 = A.t. eE/RT", "optd": "\u0394 = A.t.T", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The del factor (\u0394) increases as the final number of cells", "opta": "decreases", "optb": "increases", "optc": "zero", "optd": "constant", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The overall del factor (\u0394) may be represented as", "opta": "\u0394overall = \u0394heating + \u0394holding- \u0394cooling", "optb": "\u0394overall = \u0394heating + \u0394holding+ \u0394cooling", "optc": "\u0394overall = \u0394heating - \u0394holding+ \u0394cooling", "optd": "\u0394overall = \u0394heating - \u0394holding- \u0394cooling", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The filter material used for air filtration system is/are", "opta": "glass wool", "optb": "glass fibre", "optc": "norite", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The deviation from ideal plug flow due to axial mixing can be described by the", "opta": "dispersion model", "optb": "Langmuir model", "optc": "Friedlander model", "optd": "Pasceri model", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The collection efficiency by diffusion increases with", "opta": "decreasing particle size", "optb": "decreasing air velocity", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "increasing particle size", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Glass fibers are favorable as a filter medium because they give a", "opta": "lower pressure drop and are less liable to wetting or combustion", "optb": "more pressure drop and are less liable to wetting or combustion", "optc": "lower pressure drop and are more liable to wetting or combustion", "optd": "more pressure drop and are more liable to wetting or combustion", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The collection efficiency by interception increases with the", "opta": "increasing particle diameter", "optb": "increasing air flow velocity", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "increasing particle size", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For indirect heating, the plate and frame heat exchanger is generally more effective than the shell and tube heat transfer due to its", "opta": "larger heat transfer area", "optb": "smaller heat transfer area", "optc": "lesser cost", "optd": "more number of plates", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mechanism of air filtration in fibrous filter is", "opta": "electrostatic attraction", "optb": "impaction", "optc": "interception", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the packing density (\u03b1) is defined as the volume of the fiber unit volume of filter bed, the velocity within the filter void space is equal to (where V is velocity in fluid void space and V0 is undisturbed fluid velocity)", "opta": "V = V0/(1-\u03b1)", "optb": "V-V0 = 1 - \u03b1", "optc": "V = V0(1 - \u03b1)", "optd": "V = V0/(1 + \u03b1)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the turbulent flow, the dispersion coefficient is correlated as a function of", "opta": "Reynolds number", "optb": "Sherwood number", "optc": "Schmidt number", "optd": "Grashof number", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In sterilization process, spore of which of the following organism is considered as control?", "opta": "Bacillus subtilis", "optb": "Clostridium botulinum", "optc": "Bacillus stearothermophilus", "optd": "Aspergillus niger", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Analogus to the molecular diffusion, the x-directional flux of microorganisms suspended in a medium due to the axial mixing can be represented as (where Jn is flux component 'n', cn is concentration of'n')", "opta": "Jn = -dcn/dx", "optb": "Jn = dcn/dx", "optc": "Jn = -D dcn/dx", "optd": "Jn = D dcn/dx", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The typical size of particles collected by diffusion mechanism is", "opta": "<0.25\u03bcm", "optb": "<0.5\u03bcm", "optc": "<0.75\u03bcm", "optd": "<1\u03bcm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The X90 value for a filtration system is", "opta": "the time required to reduce microbial population by 90%", "optb": "the time required to traverse survivor curve by one log cycle.", "optc": "the depth required to reduce population by 90%", "optd": "the depth of the filter required to reduce population by 99%", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The value of K", "opta": "increases with increase in air velocity", "optb": "decreases with increase in air velocity", "optc": "increases to an optimum with increase in air velocity and decreases on further increase of air velocity", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Model proposed by the Friedlander, correlating the air filtration efficiency by impaction can be expressed as (where NSt is the Stokes number)", "opta": "\u03b7imp =  0.075NSt1.2", "optb": "\u03b7imp =  0.75NSt1.2", "optc": "\u03b7imp = 0.25NSt1.2", "optd": "\u03b7imp = 0.025NSt1.2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The collection efficiency by impaction increases with", "opta": "increasing particle diameter", "optb": "increasing air flow velocity", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "increasing particle size", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The efficiency of fibrous filter by combined mechanism is given by(where \u03b7imp,\u03b7int,\u03b7dif are the efficiencies by impaction, interception and diffusion respectively)", "opta": "1 - \u03b7imp\u03b7int\u03b7dif", "optb": "1 - (1 - \u03b7imp)(1 - \u03b7int)( 1 - \u03b7dif)", "optc": "1 - ( \u03b7imp\u03b7int/\u03b7dif)", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The heat conduction in dry air is", "opta": "less rapid than in steam", "optb": "more rapid than in steam", "optc": "similar to steam", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For laminar flow of Newtonian fluid through a smooth round pipe, the ratio of average fluid velocity to the maximum velocity is", "opta": "0.5", "optb": "0.75", "optc": "0.87", "optd": "0.37", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reduction of number of cells from 1010 to one will result into the del factor (\u0394) of", "opta": "1", "optb": "10", "optc": "23", "optd": "103", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sterilization can be carried out by", "opta": "heat", "optb": "radiation", "optc": "chemical agents", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The collection efficiency by the inertial impaction mechanism is the function of", "opta": "Stokes and Reynolds number", "optb": "Stokes and Schmidt number", "optc": "Grashoff and Reynolds number", "optd": "Stokes and Grashof number", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The heated medium passes through a holding section, which is usually maintained in", "opta": "adiabatic conditions", "optb": "isothermal conditions", "optc": "isotropic conditions", "optd": "isobaric conditions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The highest temperature which appears to be feasible for batch sterilization is", "opta": "121\u00b0C", "optb": "100\u00b0C", "optc": "105\u00b0C", "optd": "130\u00b0C", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The K used in the equation for X10=2.303/K depends upon", "opta": "nature of the filter material", "optb": "linear velocity of the air passing through filter", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "thickness of the filter", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mechanical means of accomplishing sterilization of fermentation media/equipment is", "opta": "ultrasonic", "optb": "radiation", "optc": "chemical agents", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The radius of the filter with a depth of 14 cm required for a volumetric airflow rate of 10 m3/min is approximately", "opta": "1.6 m", "optb": "0.6 m", "optc": "3", "optd": "6 m", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The moist heat is more effective than the dry heat because the intrinsic heat resistance of vegetative cells is greatly", "opta": "increased in a dry state", "optb": "decreased in a dry state", "optc": "increased in a wet state", "optd": "decreased in a wet state", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The destruction of microorganisms by steam may be described as", "opta": "first order chemical reaction", "optb": "zero order chemical reaction", "optc": "second order chemical reaction", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Typical aeration rates for aerobic fermentation are", "opta": "0 - 0.5 vvm", "optb": "0.5 - 1.0 vvm", "optc": "1.0 - 1.5 vvm", "optd": "1.5 - 2.0 vvm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}